Hello friends, you gave a very good response to the previous video Top 10
Health Insurance Companies in India 2025.
So
people raised a lot of questions on it and asked
about different policies of different companies.
So for this, in this video
I am going to compare some of the policies in detail.
And I have selected the six companies from which
you had asked maximum questions.
HDFC AGO's Optima Secure comes at the top,
I have received the maximum number of questions about it.  After that K Supreme,
then Nivvi Bar Raho 2.0, Aitya
Birla's Active Fit, Bajaj Ali's Health
Gard Gold and ICICI LMA's Max
product, so we will compare the policies of these six companies
in this video.
What is their eligibility criteria max cover?  What are Key Points?
What are the additional benefits that each one receives
?  And what are the must-have riders that
come with these policies?  So this is what we are going to
see in this video.
I have tried to simplify as usual.
So I am Mahesh from Truck Book India and after
working in research and development for 30 years,
I resigned.  So that I
can see my beautiful country.  So now let us see,
if you want to join these six companies that I have selected, then what will be their age criteria
?  What is the maximum cover they provide
?  And how is the room rent coverage?  Ok?
So, what I have highlighted in yellow color is
HDFC RGO's Opt Secure, Niv BPA
's Reo 2.0, Bajaj Allians' Health Guard
Gold and ICICI LBRD's Max Protect. If
you look at all these policies, the
maximum age is 65 years.  The
entry age is 18 years and you can take this policy till 65 years.
So for senior citizen
you will have to select another policy.
And there is another one which is Max Protect of ICICI LBRD,
you can take it even from the age of six years.
So this policy will be good for children also.
After that comes
Supreme of Care and Active Fit of Aditya Birla,
I have highlighted both of them in green
because their entry age is 18
and the second age limit which is 65 years is capped
for other companies.  There
is no maximum capping for specific policies.  So
if there is a senior citizen in your house,
you want to buy it for your parents or you
yourself are a senior citizen and you
want to buy some health insurance after
retirement, then Care Supreme and Aditya
Birla's Active Fit are suitable for you.
After that let us see what maximum cover
is possible.  You will see that
I have highlighted the Health Guard Gold of Bajaj Ali
because its max
cap gives cover only up to Rs 50 lakh and
nowadays I have my own insurance,
I have taken health
insurance of almost Rs 1 crore for me and my wife,
so nowadays health and
hospital treatments have become so costly that I
feel that there should be health insurance of up to Rs 1 crore.
So this seemed a bit of a
negative point to me.  So
I have highlighted it for this.  Now we will see
that Aditya Birla's Active Fit can
give you coverage up to Rs 6 crore.  And
ICICI LBD's Max Protect can
give you coverage up to Rs 10 crore.  So if
you want,
you can take health cover up to Rs 10 crore.  Now let's come to
room rent.  You can see that
all the policies I have selected are the
best policies of the same companies.  So
no room rent capping in all.  Ok?  Only the
two policies I selected, Bajaj Aliz and ICICI LBA,
cover everything except Accept Suit.  So if you take a suite room,
I feel that the focus of your prime
treatment is for yourself and
not for someone taking a suite or a big
luxurious room, I feel that I do
not need it.  So all the
policies that I have selected have no room
rent capping which is very good.  Now let's come to the
points.  So in the key point
you can see that HDFC Ergo's
Optima Secure starts giving 2x to 3x cover from
day one depending on
what you have selected and
can give 4x to 5x if you have taken Plus & Secure
benefit, then this is a rider, so if
you have taken it then you can get 4x to 5x benefit also
and that too coverage can be given from day one,
after that coming to Care
Supreme, we had seen that it is
good for senior citizens, there is no entry age
and it gives up to five x cover, giving
you V Super No Low Claim benefit.  Ok
?  Next comes the NIV bua up to
10x cover V-Booster Plus.  But see, you
get 10X cover only if you have taken its Platinum and Titanium plan.  Otherwise, if you have taken the Gold plan,
you get up to 5x benefit.
And the new BUPA provides age lock benefit
which I liked very much because
I have written it here, see, there is
lock the clock benefit, so
what happens in the Reor 2.0 plan is that if
you do not take any claim then your
premium remains fixed.
That premium does not change according to your age.
This is a very good thing.  Because the
age related premium keeps
increasing gradually.  If you do
not claim it, it will be locked.  Let's say lock the
clock.  After that comes
Aditya Birla's Active Fit.  So
what happens in this is that the chronic diseases that exist start getting
covered from day one.  You get up to
5X cover with Super Credit.
After that, the
good thing about Bajaj Allians High Guard Gold is that it provides
maternity cover.  Okay, and in the
Max Protect of ICICI LB, I had
already told you that you can get very high coverage up to Rs 10 crore.
Very high
coverage can be obtained and global coverage
is available.  So if you are a frequent traveler then
definitely it is better that you get a global
coverage.  So I found this benefit
in ICICI Board policy.  After that comes
other benefits.  Ok?  So
in this I have taken Restore Point Wellness Benefit
and pre and post coverage
of expenses.  So
what does restore benefit mean?  So
here I have explained a little bit.
You can see later that if you get
hospitalized in that policy year when you have paid the full premium and
suppose you have taken a policy of Rs 10 lakh and Rs 10 lakh gets
consumed, then after the entire amount is consumed,
it gets
retopped up immediately.  Ok?  So you
can
see that the unlimited top-up of the companies that I have
highlighted in green, Care Nivea Bhupa
Aditya Birla and ICICI LBAD,
is available to you.  Ok?   No matter
how many times you run out of money,
it will be automatically topped up.  Which is a
very good thing in fact.  And if we talk about HDFC IGO
and Bajaj Allianz, their top-up is done once a
year up to some extent.  But
I have highlighted here a little bit
that if you take an add-on in HDFC IGO
then you can get unlimited top-ups.
So keep this in mind, if you are going to
select HDFC IGO policy
then what do you have to do?  You have to take unlimited add ons.
After that comes the wellness
benefit.
You can see I have highlighted it in green color.
Care Nivapa and Aditya
Birla all offer wellness benefits.   For
example, if you walk daily steps and
they log it in their apps etc.,
then they definitely give you some benefit in terms of
your premium.
Ok?  There is
no other benefit in it.  After that, the
pre and post expenses of Aditya Birla include
your scanning many times before your hospitalization.  I
get some medicines myself.  After that,
if the treatment is not successful then only the
doctor suggests hospitalization to you.
So your 90 days can be
covered in advance and later it can be covered up to 180 days.
Which is very good.  Your coverage will continue for six months.
Even after hospitalization, there are many medicines which are
very costly.  There are injections
which cover everything.
Aditya Birla is giving the highest benefit.  All the remaining
five companies give you benefits within 60 days, i.e. 2 months
before and 6 months after.
So all the policies are good.
As I said, I have
selected good policies while selecting the policy.
After that comes the must have
riders.  So keep in mind that the pre-
existing waiting period for diseases
is the shortest
in ICICI LBD's Max Protect.
In other cases, you may have to wait for three to four years, four years or even six
years. There may be
some pre-existing diseases, so the
shorter it is, the better it is for you because by then,
you will get
coverage as soon as possible. After that, if
something serious happens to you or there is a
serious hospitalization, then you can
get coverage. After that,
what is the disease-wise sub-limit? If we talk about it, then if the
sub-disease is like this, then the coverage will not be immediate
or the coverage amount will be less. There are some
riders like this. All the policies that I have
selected here do not have those riders.
Only Aditya Birla has given a
rider for maternity, no one else has
given any rider. So, all the
disease-wise sub-limits are there, are they
correct in the policy?  So I think that's all.
This was a very brief and
quick session for you.  It is very
important to know that whenever you want to take health insurance,
you should definitely study it thoroughly yourself.
As well as if possible, if
you have an insurance advisor then it would be
better to take advice from him.
Because we don't understand ourselves much and
sometimes we can make mistakes.  In
case you are confident that you want to take it, then
online applications of every company
are also available.  My observation is that
if you buy from an agent, the
premium may be a little higher and if you
purchase directly online, then many
times the companies also give you some discount.
So, as a sample and example, I have given
you HDFC Ergo.
If you want to apply for HDFC Ergo insurance online, then let
me
quickly show you how to do it.  This link which I have
given, I have given this link here
in the description of the video.  If you just
click on it, you will directly
go to the HDFCO page, which will make it easier for you.
So you can just check at
least what your premium is
and after that you can ask the agent what
premium he is telling you for the same policy and the same riders or if you want to compare with any other
company then
you can check every company online like this.
Let's just click on that link and
see where we are going.
Ok?  Let's go.  So you
can see if I click on this link then
you will go to the HDFC Ergo page.
Ok?  Here you can see that here
they have given for online application.
If as I say
Optima is secure for me.  What if I
want to buy online?
You will get complete details here.  Like if
I select self plus wife.
I put the edge.  55 I'll
put
50 here.  I am just posting this for representation.
We take Rs 10 lakh insurance.
Suppose here comes Deki Directly Sale
For Wife.  Okay, after that we will
enter
our pin code and after that we will enter our mobile number
and after viewing the plan I will click.  He is
taking OTP, I will enter that OTP.
So you can see he has
paid a premium of ₹34.46 for Optima Secure for Rs 10 lakh.  Four X
cover ok no room cap wider free and post
hospitalization ok so in this way you will
get it immediately that what will happen if you
take an exact family floater
?  How much premium will you get?  And if
you say buy now then you
can buy it by paying the money.  So if you
want riders etc. then by clicking No More you
can see as many riders etc. as possible,
what are the policies in it, what is covered in it,
what is not covered, after seeing all this you
can buy it.  So it is so easy to buy online.
So I think that's all.  If you have any questions, please
ask.  But at this time I will
not be able to answer much.  Because I am travelling
and if you post some comment and
my reply does not come for 8 days then understand
that I am out.  Because I am going to
Uttarakhand now.  So since it is summer season,
it definitely happens and for this I will be a
little busy.  So if you do
n't get any response then I am sorry for that.
I will tell you in advance.  I will try
not to have a butt signal to respond to you.  There will be
no coverage there.  Because I am going to
a village.  So it
is quite difficult for this.  So for this I say
that there may be a slight delay in response.
So thank you so much.  And Buy For Now.
Do subscribe and share my channel.